{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Ford","incorrectAnswers":["BMW","AC","Honda"],"question":"Which car manufacturer makes the Model T?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The influences of celestial bodies on earthly affairs","incorrectAnswers":["Friction at very small scale","The Sun","Men"],"question":"What is astrology the study of?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Low Blood Pressure","incorrectAnswers":["Tight Muscles","Torn Ligaments","Weak Tendons"],"question":"What Would You Suffer From With Hypotension?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Tiger","incorrectAnswers":["Elephant","Lion","Crocodile"],"question":"What is the national animal of India?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Sweet Smell of Success","incorrectAnswers":["Network","It's A Wonderful Life","The Shining"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'J. J. Hunsecker'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Face cards","incorrectAnswers":["Number cards","Lord cards","Icon cards"],"question":"What term is used to describe the cards in a deck that have either a Jack, Queen, or King on the card?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"William Shakespeare","incorrectAnswers":["Arthur C. Clarke","Isaac Newton","Enid Blyton"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Twelfth Night'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Camp Crystal Lake","incorrectAnswers":["Camp Fear","Camp Last Retreat","Camp Snowy Peaks"],"question":"What Is The Name Of The Summer Camp In The Friday The 13th Movies?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Trinidad and Tobago","incorrectAnswers":["Argentina","Paraguay","Peru"],"question":"Port of Spain is a city in which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"City of God","incorrectAnswers":["Die Hard","Unforgiven","A Beautiful Mind"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'In the slums of Rio, two kids' paths diverge as one becomes a photographer and the other a kingpin.'","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Anne Boleyn","incorrectAnswers":["Catherine of Aragon","Anne of Cleves","Catherine Parr"],"question":"Who Was The 2nd Wife Of Henry VIII?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Eucalyptus","incorrectAnswers":["Lavender","Bamboo","Peppermint"],"question":"What leaves form the majority of a Koala's diet?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Daniel Day-Lewis","incorrectAnswers":["Bradley Cooper","Hugh Jackman","Joaquin Phoenix"],"question":"Who won the 2012 Academy Award for Best Leading Actor for playing the role of Abraham Lincoln in Lincoln?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jaws","incorrectAnswers":["The Silence of the Lambs","The Good, the Bad and the Ugly","Platoon"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A killer shark unleashes chaos on a beach community.'","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Kurt Vonnegut","incorrectAnswers":["Ernest Hemingway","Roald Dahl","Virginia Woolf"],"question":"Who wrote the novels \"Slaughterhouse Five\" and \"Breakfast Of Champions\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Pristina","incorrectAnswers":["Lomé","Monrovia","Zagreb"],"question":"What is the capital city of Kosovo?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Shutter speed","incorrectAnswers":["Focal length","Aperture","ISO settings"],"question":"Which setting would photographers adjust to prevent fast moving targets becoming blurred?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Black Forest Gateau","incorrectAnswers":["Apple Strudel","Pavlova","Profiteroles"],"question":"Which dessert is named after the German region in which it originated?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Charlotte, Emily, Anne","incorrectAnswers":["Ashley, Charlotte Margaret","Charlotte, Emily, Mary","Anne, Emily, Margaret"],"question":"What are the names of the three Brontë sisters?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Nothing is arduous for the willing","incorrectAnswers":["Let them hate so long as they fear","Seize the wine","I am not led, I lead"],"question":"How does that Latin phrase 'Nil volentibus arduum' translate into English?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Football","incorrectAnswers":["Athletics","Motor racing","Basketball"],"question":"With which sport is Pele associated?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"38th President of the USA. ","incorrectAnswers":["Developed the world's first vaccine (for smallpox).","Italian explorer who landed in America.","Dictator of Nazi Germany."],"question":"Which of the following describes John F. Kennedy?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Otter","incorrectAnswers":["Squirrel","Turtle","Bear"],"question":"What Sort Of Animal Was Tarka?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1996","incorrectAnswers":["1986","1991","2001"],"question":"In which year was a mammal first cloned?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Calf","incorrectAnswers":["A Caterpillar","A Kit","A Lamb"],"question":"What is the word for a young moose?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Yo, Adrian!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"May the odds ever be in your favor.\"","\"Just keep swimming.\"","\"A martini. Shaken, not stirred.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Rocky'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Friends","incorrectAnswers":["Seinfeld","The Office","Band of Brothers"],"question":"What Emmy-winning show did Lisa Kudrow star in?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1947","incorrectAnswers":["1945","1938","1955"],"question":"In which year did the Cold War between the U.S. and Soviet Union begin?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A yoke","incorrectAnswers":["A drove","A troop","A run"],"question":"What is the word for a group of oxen?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Belarus","incorrectAnswers":["Moldova","Liberia","Germany"],"question":"Minsk is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Port of Spain","incorrectAnswers":["Mogadishu","Dili","Maseru"],"question":"What is the capital city of Trinidad and Tobago?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Gardyloo","incorrectAnswers":["Halfpace","Oxter","Nudiustertian"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'used in Edinburgh as a warning cry when it was customary to throw slops from the windows into the streets'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Green","incorrectAnswers":["Red","Blue","Purple"],"question":"What colour is wasabi?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Hapsburgs","incorrectAnswers":["The Tudors","Medicis","The Rothschilds"],"question":"Which family held the position of Holy Roman Emperor almost uninterrupted from 1438 to 1806?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"6","incorrectAnswers":["2","20","10"],"question":"What Do The Lyrics In The 1st Line Of The Elvis Presley Song “Blue Suede Shoes” Add Up To?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Forget it, Jake, it's Chinatown.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"I could do this all day\"","\"You shall not pass!\"","\"Mother of mercy, is this the end of Rico?\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Chinatown'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Pink Floyd","incorrectAnswers":["Wings","Rudimental","The Alan Parsons Project"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'Have a Cigar'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Zanzibar","incorrectAnswers":["Australia","Iceland","Hispaniola"],"question":"What island is known as the Spice Island?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Afghanistan ","incorrectAnswers":["Iraq","Bangladesh","Sri Lanka"],"question":"In which Asian country is the Hindu Kush mountain range?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Saul Bellow","incorrectAnswers":["Ernest Hemingway","F. Scott Fitzgerald","William Faulkner"],"question":"Who is the author of the novels 'Von Humboldt Fleisher', 'Augie March', and 'Moses Herzog'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Germany","incorrectAnswers":["Russia","South Africa","South Korea & Japan"],"question":"Which country hosted the 2006 FIFA World Cup?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Manchurian Candidate","incorrectAnswers":["The Shining","M","The Silence of the Lambs"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Mrs. Iselin'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Kirk Douglas","incorrectAnswers":["Clint Eastwood","Burt Lancaster","Anthony Hopkins"],"question":"Which actor is the father-in-law of Catherine Zeta-Jones?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Jan van Eyck","incorrectAnswers":["‎Salvador Dalí","Cassius Marcellus Coolidge","Sandro Botticelli"],"question":"Which artist painted \"The Arnolfini Marriage\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Gomiti","incorrectAnswers":["Rotelle","Bigoli","Campanelle"],"question":"Which pasta's name means 'Elbows'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Set them free","incorrectAnswers":["Put a ring on them","Hold them tight","Never let them go"],"question":"What does the singer Sting suggest you should do if you love somebody?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Antarctica ","incorrectAnswers":["Australia","New Zealand","Scotland"],"question":"Where would you find the Queen Alexandra, Queen Elizabeth and Queen Maud mountain ranges?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Circe","incorrectAnswers":["Medusa","Calypso","Aphrodite"],"question":"In Ancient Greek mythology, which enchantress changes Ulysses' men into pigs, but also warns him about the sirens?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Jurassic","incorrectAnswers":["Mesozoic","Triassic","Devonian"],"question":"In Geology What Period followed The Cretaceous?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Peleus and Thetis","incorrectAnswers":["Perseus and Persephone","Hera and Zeus","Daedalus and Penelope"],"question":"In Greek mythology, who were Achilles' parents?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"They're GR-R-R-reat!","incorrectAnswers":["A glass and a half in every half pound","Finger lickin' good","Breakfast of Champions"],"question":"What is the marketing slogan of Kelloggs Frosties?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Drew Barrymore","incorrectAnswers":["Penélope Cruz","Kirsten Dunst","Charlize Theron"],"question":"Which actor has played roles in films including Batman Forever and Donnie Darko?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Gasket","incorrectAnswers":["Circuit","Fuse","Bolt"],"question":"What is the name of the piece used to cover the intersection between two surfaces, usually to prevent leaking?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Gallo Pinto","incorrectAnswers":["Polenta","Taco","Ropa Vieja"],"question":"Which of these dishes would you most expect to find in Costa Rica?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Hemisphere","incorrectAnswers":["Equator","Pangaea","Continent"],"question":"What is the name used for any half of the globe?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Catherine the Great","incorrectAnswers":["Tatyana the Great","Alexandra the Great","Ludmilla the Great"],"question":"Who was the most renowned and longest-ruling female leader of Russia?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Golf","incorrectAnswers":["Sailing","Tennis","Athletics"],"question":"Which sport is played at The US PGA?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Ector","incorrectAnswers":["Uther","Constantine","Guinevere"],"question":"Who was King Arthur's foster-father?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Martin Luther King Jr.","incorrectAnswers":["John F Kennedy","Malcolm X","John Lennon"],"question":"Who said 'I've looked over, & I've seen the promised land' one day before his assassination?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Ritchie Valens","incorrectAnswers":["Buddy Holly","Eddie Cochran","Chuck Berry"],"question":"Who performed the song 'La Bamba'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Socialist state","incorrectAnswers":["Constitutional monarchy","Representative democracy","Aristocracy"],"question":"What kind of country did Cuba become under Fidel Castro?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The Pancreas","incorrectAnswers":["Thyroid","Cyretic","Insuloid"],"question":"Which gland produces insulin?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Glazing pastry","incorrectAnswers":["Cleaning vegetables","Icing cakes","Cocktail bases"],"question":"Eggwash is generally used for what purpose?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Queen","incorrectAnswers":["A Worker","A Soar","A Pen"],"question":"A female cat is known as what?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Hermana","incorrectAnswers":["Familia","Amor","Nina"],"question":"What term of endearment is appropriate for your sister in Spanish?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Red","incorrectAnswers":["White","Blue","Nine"],"question":"What does the word 'rot' mean in German?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Buenos Aires","incorrectAnswers":["Sao Paolo","Cordoba","Santiago"],"question":"Name the capital of Argentina.","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Kosher ","incorrectAnswers":["Deli","Vegan","Halal"],"question":"Food that is permitted to be eaten under Jewish dietary laws is known as what?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Pizza ","incorrectAnswers":["Burger","Pasta","Steak"],"question":"A Calzone Is A Folded Stuffed What?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Jaundice","incorrectAnswers":["Eczema","Psoriasis","Hemophilia"],"question":"What is the name of the medical condition marked by yellow discoloring of the skin caused by too much bilirubin in the blood?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Harry Potter","incorrectAnswers":["Voyages Extraordinaires","Percy Jackson & the Olympians","Twilight"],"question":"In which book series does 'Peter Pettigrew' appear?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Lake Victoria","incorrectAnswers":["Lake Huron","Lake Baikal","Lake Malawi"],"question":"What lake is the source of the White Nile?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"James Cameron","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed Titanic?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Poco","incorrectAnswers":["Torro","Loco","Mucho"],"question":"What is the Spanish word for \"few\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A boy and his little sister struggle to survive in Japan during World War II.","incorrectAnswers":["POWs are forced to build a railway, not knowing that allies are planning to destroy it.","An aspiring nun is sent to become a governess to the seven children of a widowed naval officer.","Eddy has a week to pay back £500,000 after losing a poker game to a powerful local mobster."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Grave of the Fireflies?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Russian","incorrectAnswers":["Indian","French","Egyptian"],"question":"What was the nationality of Rasputin?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Southeast Asia","incorrectAnswers":["The Amazon","The European Steppes","Central America"],"question":"The Rafflesia Has The Largest Single Flower Of Any Plant In The World. Where In The World Does It Grow?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Van Morrison","incorrectAnswers":["Cat Stevens","David Bowie","Bob Dylan"],"question":"'Moondance' was a hit for which male singer?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1996","incorrectAnswers":["1992","2000","2004"],"question":"In which year was Fargo first released in the cinema?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Estonia","incorrectAnswers":["Kyrgyzstan","Tajikistan","Uzbekistan"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Russia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"4","incorrectAnswers":["3","0","1"],"question":"In Charles Dickens' \"A Christmas Carol\", how many different ghosts visited Scrooge?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Mischa Barton","incorrectAnswers":["Rachel Bilson","Misha Collins","Megan Fox"],"question":"Which actress played the character Marissa on 'The O.C.' and later became a model on 'The Beautiful Life'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Washington Irving","incorrectAnswers":["Suzanne Collins","James Fenimore Cooper","Donna Leon"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Le Livre d’esquisses'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"plankton","incorrectAnswers":["interactions among organisms and the water cycle","the Islam","society"],"question":"What is Planktology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Alexandre Dumas","incorrectAnswers":["Anatole France","Gustave Flaubert","Charles Perrault"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Count of Monte Cristo'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Africa","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Oceania","Europe"],"question":"The country of Equatorial Guinea is on which continent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Cow","incorrectAnswers":["A Worker","A Jenny","A Soar"],"question":"What is a female walrus known as?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Lyndon Johnson","incorrectAnswers":["William H. Taft","Donald J. Trump","Harry S. Truman"],"question":"Who was the 36th president of the USA, in term during the period 1963–1969?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"DNA","incorrectAnswers":["RNA","DRA","DA"],"question":"Deoxyribonucleic acid is better known as what?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Eris","incorrectAnswers":["Enyo","Ersa","Eleos"],"question":"Who is the Greek equivalent of the roman god Discordia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Diamonds","incorrectAnswers":["Frankincense","Myrhh","Gold"],"question":"Which of the following was not a gift from one of the biblical wise men?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Eyes & Lips","incorrectAnswers":["Head & Toes","Arms & Legs","Chest & Hips"],"question":"What 2 Parts Of The Body Are The First To Be Mentioned In The Song \"You've Lost That Loving Feeling\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Valetudinarian","incorrectAnswers":["Fudgel","Lackadaisical","Groke"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'a sickly or weak person, especially one who is constantly and morbidly concerned with his or her health'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Michael Jackson","incorrectAnswers":["Nicki Minaj","Neil Young","Eric Clapton"],"question":"Who released the song 'Off the Wall'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Moses","incorrectAnswers":["Mohammed","Frodo","Buddha"],"question":"Who of these was a key figure of Jewish/Christian history?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"USA","incorrectAnswers":["France","Italy","Netherlands"],"question":"Which country produces the most cheese in the world?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Dieci","incorrectAnswers":["Zehn","Dez","Otto"],"question":"In Italian, what is the word for for 'ten'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ashgabat","incorrectAnswers":["Lusaka","Antananarivo","Addis Ababa"],"question":"What is the capital city of Turkmenistan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Bangkok","incorrectAnswers":["Kuala Lumpur","Sao Paolo","Singapore"],"question":"As what is Krung Thep is more commonly known?","difficulty":"hard"},